杰森:早上好.
Jason: Good morning.
麦琪:早上好,杰森.我收到第一封专栏的读者来信了.
Maggie: Morning, Jason.I just got my first fan letter from my column.
杰森:好.太好了.信上说什么了?
Jason: Good.That's wonderful.What's it say?
麦琪:亲爱的马龙小姐,
Maggie: Dear Miss Malone,
我从来就没想到猫产仔会有那么有趣.
I've never really given much thought to kitty litter,
不过您最近的大作让我大开眼界.
but your recent article opened my eyes.
现在我向您发誓,也许有一天我也去弄一只……猫.
Now I swear by "Tabby Fresh." Perhaps one day I'll get a ...... cat.
杰森:很好.
Jason: Nice.
本:早上好.
Ben: Morning.
麦琪:好.
Maggie: Morning.
本:哦,爸爸,
Ben: Um, dad, I don't want you to be mad,
我不想让您生气,但我找不着历史课本了.
but I can't find my history book.
杰森:我为什么要生气呢?
Jason: Why would I be mad?
本,我不是没有课本去上课的那个人,
I'm not the one who has to go to class without a book, Ben.
而且我也不是那个还没准备就考试的人.
I'm not the one who has to take a test unprepared.
本:不,但你是那个必须花25块钱让我再买一本的人.
Ben: No, but you're the one who has to cough up 25 bucks to replace it.
杰森:不,不,不,不……我很抱歉,
Jason: No, no, no, no, no...I'm sorry, you're not listening, Ben.
你没听我的话,本.不,我这次不会帮你了.
No, I'm not gonna bail you out this time.
本:你说的对,爸爸.
Ben: You're right, dad, it's time for a tough love lesson.
现在该对我上一堂粗暴父爱的课了.我要跌出前五名了,
I'm gonna drop out of fifth period.I can always sell "Mary Kay."
我还要到大街上去卖艺,我的皮肤很不错.
I've got good skin.
麦琪:够了,本.杰森,给他25块钱.
Maggie: Enough, Ben.Jason, give him twenty-five dollars.
杰森:(叹气)我只有两张20的.
Jason: (groaning) I've only got two twenties here.
本:你真是小气.
Ben: You're a prince.
迈克:你好!哦,来份煎鸡蛋,快点.
Mike: Hello!Ah, scrambled, please.
杰森:嘿,迈克,
Jason: Hey, Mike, did it ever occur to you that your mother is not just
你是不是觉得她不是你妈妈,而是一个女佣呢?
some domestic drudge?
迈克:不.呃,
Mike: No.Uh, dad, listen,
爸爸,听我说,我一门大学课程出了个小问题.
I'm having a little problem with one of my college classes.
杰森:不及格了?
Jason: Attending:
迈克:不不,爸爸.我似乎找不着我社会学课本了.
Mike: No, no, dad.I just can't seem to find my sociology book.
杰森:如果我不给你25块钱买本新的,
Jason: And you're probably gonna have to sell "Mary Kay" if I don't come
你是不是要街上去卖艺呢?
up with 25 bucks to replace it.
迈克:不,我去卖身.啊,不过,
Mike: No, it was "Thigh-masters."
爸爸,实际上,你得给我35块.
Ah, but dad, actually it was thirty-five dollars.
麦琪:迈克,
Maggie: Mike, Ben just took your father's last forty dollars for his lost
本刚才拿走你爸爸最后40块钱去买历史课本了.
history book.
迈克:(笑)那个臭小子!
Mike: (laughing) That little leach!
麦琪:哦,我希望你也可以吃迈克的鸡蛋.
Maggie: Well, I hope you can eat Mike's eggs, too.
杰森:抱歉.
Jason: Sorry.
麦琪:(尖叫)
Maggie: (screaming)
杰森:好了,我努力一下.
Jason: Okay, I'll try.
麦琪:黛比·迪哈特获得了普利策新闻奖?
Maggie: Debbie Teighart won the Pulitzer Prize for journalism?
杰森:谁是黛比?
Jason: Debbie who?
麦琪:我大学时候的室友.
Maggie: My old college roommate.
杰森:你的一个老朋友得了普利策奖?太棒了.
Jason: Somebody you know won the Pulitzer?That's great.
麦琪:哦,是的.真是个好消息,可以愉快地开始新的一天了.
Maggie: Oh, yeah.Just the kind of good news you want to start your day.
杰森:你的朋友获得了普利策奖,你就这个样子?
Jason: Friend of yours wins the Pulitzer, and you puree the paper?
麦琪:杰森,你还记得黛比·迪哈特吗?
Maggie: Jason, don't you remember Debbie Teighart?
那个让我大学四年如同生活在地狱里的人
The one who made my life a living hell for four years?
杰森:没有印象了.
Jason: Doesn't ring a bell.
麦琪:就是那个"只要男人有一口气,我就爱上他"的黛比·迪哈特啊.
Maggie: Debbie "if he's breathing, I'll jump him" Teighart?
杰森:哦,呵呵,是的!是的!个子不高,深色皮肤,乱蓬蓬的发型.
Jason: Oh, ho, ho, yeah!Yeah!Short, short brunette, shag haircut?
麦琪:我早就知道!
Maggie: I knew it!
杰森:我总是对她说"不"的.
Jason: I always said "no."
麦琪:哦!杰森,她可什么事都做的出.记得教我新闻学的老教授,鲁特格先生吗?哦,呵呵,我确信她上了他的……
Maggie: Oh!Jason, she'd do anything to get ahead.Remember my old journalism professer, Mr.Rutger?Oh, ho, ho, I bet she was sleeping....
克莉丝:嗨!
Chrissy: Hi!
麦琪:……他的帐篷里了.
Maggie: ....in a canopy bed.
克莉丝:别生气,我把拼写课本丢了.
Chrissy: Don't get mad, but I lost my spelling book.
杰森:那这是不是说,呃,你要35块钱去买本新的?
Jason: Would this by any chance cost, ooooh, say, thirty-five dollars to replace?
克莉丝:哦-哦!
Chrissy: Oh-oh!
杰森:别想了,迈克!
Jason: Give it up, Mike!
迈克:我非要试试!
Mike: I had to try!
麦琪:哦,杰森,
Maggie: Oh, Jason, life is funny.
生活真有意思.人家黛比·迪哈特拿起了普利策奖,我却在拿着早点.
Here Debbie Teighart is picking up a Pulitzer, and
I'm picking up....soggy Cheeri-O's
杰森:哦,你反应太激烈了,
Jason: Oh, you're also overreacting, Maggie.
麦琪.你并不是一个整天忙家务的人.没擦干净!
You are not just a person who does menial chores all day.Missed a spot!
(笑)你是个称职的家庭主妇,麦琪.
laughing) You're a great housewife, Maggie,
(可你还是个超级棒的记者.
but you're also a damn fine journalist.
麦琪:哦,是的.
Maggie: Oh, sure.Here Debbie's writing about acid rain,
黛比现在写的是酸雨现象,我写的是……哦,真难以启齿……小猫.
and I'm writing about...well, I'll just say it....kitty doo-doo.
杰森:是的,不过,你写的非常出色.
Jason: Yeah, but you wrote the hell out of that.
麦琪:杰森,我真不懂.
Maggie: Jason, I don't understand it.
黛比以前连两个句子都连不起来,她能得普利策奖?哈!
Debbie couldn't string two sentences together, and she wins the Pulitzer?Ha!
她也许跟评委睡觉了!你觉得我很小气,
She was probably sleeping with the judges!
是不是?
You think I'm being petty, don't you?
杰森:不,不,不,不,不.
Jason: No, no, no, no, no.
麦琪:你说的对.我是小气.
Maggie: You're right, I am.
也许黛比真的成了一个优秀的记者.
You know, maybe Debbie's turned herself into a real journalist.
你知道,是个大度的人,我要打电话向她表示祝贺.
You know, I'm a big enough person.I'm going to call and congratulate her.
杰森:这样就好.
Jason: That's better.
麦琪:(打电话)是的,请帮我找一下黛比·迪哈特.是的,我是她的老朋友,麦琪·马龙,报的.
Maggie: (on phone) Yes, Debbie Teighart in features, please.Yes, this is an old friend
of hers, Maggie Malone, from the "Long Island Sentinal
是的,很要紧.她可以在8月份回我的电话!哦,
Yes, seriously.She can return my call in August!Well, uh, yes, yes!
是的,是的!我还是留个口信吧(搅拌机的噪音)
I would like to leave a message(blender noises).
本:好了,我们在来一遍.
Ben: Okay, let's go over this again.You're in the park, you see the babe.
你在公园里看到了那个小妞.你说什么?
What do you say?
克莉丝:我叫克莉丝,我迷路了.你能帮我找到我的哥哥,本吗?
Chrissy: I'm Chrissy, and I'm lost.Can you help me find my brother, Ben?
本:我的"帅"哥哥,本.
Ben: My "studdly" brother, Ben.
克莉丝:然后,我就可以得到冰激凌吗?
Chrissy: And then I get the ice cream?
迈克:告诉你了,我给你买冰激凌,
Mike: Tell you what; I'll get you some ice cream,
你什么都不用做.
and you don't have to do anything.
克莉丝:太好了!我去拿我的外衣.你去找你的女孩!
Chrissy: Great!I'll go get my coat.You find your own babes!
本:嘿!你在干什么?
Ben: Hey!What are you doing?
迈克:你坏了我的好事,现在我也来坏你的.
Mike: You blew my scam, Sam.Now I'm blowing yours.
你知道,丢课本的计策是我先想起来的.
You knew I had a whole lost book thing ready.
本:那有怎么样?我先下手了.
Ben: So?I got there first.
迈克:听着,小子,你还在咿呀学语的时候,这一手我已经玩的炉火纯青了.
Mike: Listen, Junior.I perfected that scam while you were still saying "Pisketti."
克莉丝:能给我买石板街冰激凌吗?
Chrissy: Can I get Rocky Road?
迈克:没问题!记住,
Mike: Absolutely!And remember, Chrissy;
克莉丝,这个周六的晚上,你想要谁陪你啊?
who do we ask for when we need a babysitter this Saturday night?
克莉丝:我的税哥哥,本.
Chrissy: My studdly brother, Ben.
本:这是什么东西?
Ben: What's all that stuff?
麦琪:啊,是我在大学里得的.
Maggie: Ah, some of my old college papers.
本:奖状?妈妈,你怎么不贴在墙上呢?
Ben: An award?Mom, why isn't this on the wall?
麦琪:哦,这只是小奖励.
Maggie: Oh, it's just a little award.
不过,我真的打败了50所大学里的学生,包括哈佛和耶鲁的.
But, I did beat out students from fifty schools, including Harvard and Yale.
本:哇噢!1969年!真是一件古董!嘿,这是什么?
Ben: Wow!1969!This thing's an antique!Hey, what's that?
麦琪:我20岁时立下的宏伟目标.(笑)
Maggie: A list of goals I made when I was twenty (laughing).
本:成为第一位战地女记,学会斯瓦西里语,
Ben: Become the first woman war correspondent, learn Swahili,
35岁时出版一部小说.
have a novel published by age thirty-five.
我不相信你这些目标真的都实现了.路还长着呢,妈妈.
I can't believe you actually did all these things.Way to go, mom!
麦琪:哦,是的,还没都实现呢.只是想检查检查.
Maggie: Oh, well.Not everything, I'm afraid.Just the ones that are checked.
本:哦,振作点.
Ben: Oh, come on.I mean, you did a lot of things here.
你已经做了很多事了.
I mean, how many people have actually, um, umm, ....
我是说,有多少人真的学会驾驶手排挡汽车了?
learned to drive a stick-shift?
杰森:要么让我抱着枕头睡觉,要么我们去体操馆锻炼.
Jason: Either I'm hugging a pillow, or we've got to join a gym.
哦,麦琪,别再重温你那些目标了.
Oh, Maggie, not that old list again!
麦琪:你能相信吗,我还没去过苏联呢?
Maggie: Can you believe I never toured the Soviet Union?
杰森:没去才好呢.现在没苏联了.划掉这个目标.
Jason: It's good you didn't.Now there is no Soviet Union.Check it off!
麦琪:解体的国家无所谓.这是个目标.
Maggie: Fallen nations don't count.It was a goal.
杰森:亲爱的,黛比·迪哈特那件事给你很大的刺激,是不是?
Jason: Boy, this Debbie Teighart thing has really gotten to you, hasn't it?
麦琪:哦,才不是呢.
Maggie: Oh, not at all.
黛比·迪哈特用她那吸尘器般的嘴唇拿下了破普利策奖这事我根本不在乎.
I could care less that Debbie "vacuum lips" Teighart lucked
into a stinking Pulitzer
杰森:哦,你能这么想我很高兴.
Jason: Well, I'm glad to see it's out of your system.
麦琪:杰森,这也许是黛比引起来的,
Maggie: Jason, this may have started out with Debbie, but now it's about me,
但我是为自己的那些没有实现的目标而伤心.我相信你的目标都实现了.
my failed goals.I bet you accomplished everything on your list.
杰森:哦……麦琪……算了吧,
Jason: Well....Maggie....Come on,
我也跟你一样有痛苦和失落.
I've had my share of pain and disappointment.
麦琪:什么?你没见过赫伯·阿尔帕特和提加纳布拉斯乐队吗?
Maggie: What?You never got to meet Herb Alpert and the Tijuana Brass?
杰森:我只到了门口.
Jason: I met the brass.
麦琪:谢谢你.这让我感觉好多了.
Maggie: Thank you.That makes me feel so much better.
杰森:哦!你取得了很多的成功,麦琪.你在和"第19频道"都干过.
Jason: Oh!You've had a lot of success, Maggie.You worked at Newsweek, and Channel
麦琪:别提了.两个我都辞了.
Maggie: That doesn't count.I quit both of them.
杰森:是的,
Jason: Yes, but you made a decision to do that,
不过你做出这个决定是因为你想花更多的时间照顾我们这个家,
because you wanted to spend more time with your family,
并写你的书……
and to write that book of yours....
我相信总有一天会出版的.
which I know you're going to get around to some day.
麦琪:杰森,你也看了那个读者给我写的信.
Maggie: Jason, Don't you see this letter made by a woman was green.
是什么让她害怕尝试呢?
What's afraid the test herself?
现在,我明白我开始消沉是在1972年的时候.
Now, I know exactly when I got off track it was 1972.
你还记得那一年吗?
Do you remember that year?
杰森:不记得了.
Jason: Not specifically.
麦琪:我当时在报道南达卡他州的选举.我有个机会跟着乔治·麦高文上一架直升机对他进行独家采访.
Maggie: I was covering the election in South Dakota,
and I had the chance to follow George McGovern into a helicopter and get
an exclusive interview.
杰森:我不记得有这样的采访.
Jason: I don't remember that interview.
麦琪:因为我没那个采访.我害怕的要命,不敢乘坐直升机.从此,我就一直生活在舒适的环境里.
Maggie: Because I didn't get the interview.I was too scared to get into the
chopper.I've been living in the comfort zone ever since
杰森:哦,算了吧,麦琪.你做的都是不舒适的事情.
Jason: Oh, come on, Maggie.You've done all kinds of uncomfortable things.
麦琪:比方说?
Maggie: Such as?
杰森:比方说,你参加反种族游行时挨过催泪瓦斯,
Jason: Such as; you got tear-gassed when you protested against Apartheid,
你生过孩子,你培养迈克上了电影.
you gave birth, you saw Mike in "Streetcar Named Desire."
麦琪:面对现实吧,杰森,我是个逃兵.
Maggie: Face it, Jason, I'm a quitter.
杰森:你不是,麦琪.
Jason: You're not, Maggie.You're still a young woman.
你还很年轻,你有足够的时间做你想做的.
You got all kinds of time to do whatever you want.
麦琪:我不能再浪费一天的时间了,杰森,
Maggie: Not if I put it off for one more day.
我要实现这张单子上的所有目标.
Jason, I'm gonna master the things on this list!
杰森:好的.
Jason: Okay
麦琪:先从第六个目标开始!
Maggie: Starting with number six!
杰森:第六个.
Jason: Number six.
麦琪:攀岩!
Maggie: Rappel down a mountain!
杰森:哦,不.
Jason: Oh, no.
麦琪:但我要挑战自己.
Maggie: But I need to challenge myself.
杰森:好吧.是,
Jason: All right, yeah.
那好.试试第18个目标:学弹吉他.
Well then, try number eighteen; learn to play the sitar.
这跟爬山一样的富有挑战性,但安全的多.
All the challenge of rock climbing, and a much higher survival rate.
麦琪:杰森,我不想后半辈子还这样畏畏缩缩,
Maggie: Jason, I don't want to spend the rest of my life hiding from the
不敢尝试让我害怕的事.
things that frighten me.
杰森:好的,那好.但是攀岩这种事,
Jason: Okay, fine, fine.But rappelling down a mountain, Maggie?
麦琪?算了吧,你不是认真的.
Come on, you can't be serious.
杰森:好吧,你是认真的.不过,非得我陪你去吗?
Jason: Okay, you're serious, but do I have to go with you?
肯特:哦,你看.这绳子很结实.真是结实极了.你可以吊上一头大象.看!
Kent: Ah, now see, this double figure-eight, Mag, this is, this is great.I mean, you can an elephant with that.Look!
杰森:(大叫)哦!抓住.
Jason: (yelling) Oh!Hold on.
肯特:你们练习过,是不是?
Kent: You've been practicing, haven't you.
麦琪:哦,练了一阵子.
Maggie: Oh, a little bit.
杰森:一阵子?这个星期的每个晚上,
Jason: A little?Every night this week, she's tied something up.
她都把自己绑起来.收起你脸上的傻笑.
Wipe that smirk off your face.
迈克:哦,哇,呃,今天真是个好日子,是不是?
Mike: Oh, whoa, uh, I guess today's the big day, huh?
麦琪:是的,你说对了!
Maggie: Yeah, you bet!
今天,我们要去征服山岩,检验一下我们的能力.
Today we conquer a sheer rock face, and see what we're made of.
杰森:不管能力检验得怎么样,
Jason: As long as what we're made up doesn't end up spread all over the
我们也不要最后四脚朝天躺在岩石上.
sheer rock face.
肯特:哦,放松,西沃医生.
Kent: Oh, relax, Dr.Seaver.This is gonna be a day that you'll always remember.
这将是你终生难忘的一天.这一次,我保证抓紧绳子.
And this time I'm sure the ropes are gonna hold.
本:那么,呃,
Ben: So, um, you guys are gonna be gone all day,
你们要出去一整天,明天才能回来,是吗?
and won't be back'til tomorrow, right?
杰森:哦,如果你妈妈决定豁出去的话,
Jason: Well, it could last through to Monday,
我们要到周一才能回来.
if 'yer maw' decides to bag herself a 'bar.'
肯特:好.我们开始装齿轮.
Kent: Okay, let's get the gear loaded.
麦琪:好的,再见,孩子们.互相照顾着点.
Maggie: Okay, goodbye boys.Take good care of each other.
本:好的.到时候见.小心点,好好玩,保证安全.
Ben: Okay, I'll see you guys later.Be careful.Have fun, be safe.
麦琪:我们会的.
Maggie: We will.
杰森:要看着克莉丝上大学才行啊.
Jason: Make sure Chrissy goes to college.
迈克:哦,爸爸.
Mike: Oh, dad.
本:好了,我们会想你们的.
Ben: All right, we'll miss ya!
麦琪:哦!快点,杰森,努力.
Maggie: Oh!Come on, Jason, keep up.
哦,真爽快,好新鲜的空气.
Oh, it's so exhilarating in this fresh, crisp air.
杰森:我鞋子里有块石头.
Jason: I have a rock in my shoe.
麦琪:哦,今天是征服恐惧的一个好日子.
Maggie: Oh, what a perfect day to conquer your fears.
做一下深呼吸,然后走上世界的边缘.
Take a deep breath and step off the edge of the world.
肯特:(笑)我们来了.
Kent: (laughing) Well, here we are.
杰森:哦,这不像我想的那么难啊.麦琪?麦琪!
Jason: Well, that doesn't look as bad as I thought.Maggie?Maggie!
杰森:麦琪,你不能整夜都抱着这块石头啊.
Jason: Maggie, you can't keep hugging this mountain all night long.
麦琪:看啊,杰森,我怎么才能说动你也尝试一下呢?
Maggie: Watch me.Jason, how could you let me talk you into this?
杰森:我-我只是在这里给你精神支持.
Jason: I-I'm just here for moral support.
麦琪:别这样!我要的是物质支持!
Maggie: Stop that!I want physical support!I want an elevator, a ski lift!
我需要一个滑雪梯!甚至一架直升机也可以!
I'll even get in a helicopter!
杰森:她很慌张.
Jason: She's panicking.
肯特:哦,越慌张越危险.
Kent: Well, if worse comes to worst,
我随时都可以把她从岩石上用铁钩钩下来.
I can always pry her off the rock with a crampon.
杰森:你就不能说些话,让她的恐惧缓和一下吗?
Jason: Is there anything you could say to assuage her fears?
肯特:好的."缓和"是什么意思?
Kent: Okay.What does "assuage" mean?
杰森:你知道"起诉"的意思吗?
Jason: You know what "litigation" means?
麦琪:杰森,别责怪肯特.我还以为我可以做到呢.
Maggie: Jason, don't blame Kent.I thought I could do this.
肯特:你愿意我把自己的鼓舞士气的话说给她听吗?
Kent: Would you like for me to give her my customary pep talk?
杰森:那太好了.
Jason: That would be nice.
肯特:好的.既然上去,必须下来.
Kent: Okay.What goes up must come down.
麦琪:把这句话记下来,杰森.写到我的墓碑上.
Maggie: Remember that Jason.I want it on my tombstone.
杰森:麦琪,我要说的是你告诉我的话.征服这座山只是你实现所有目标的第一步.
Jason: Maggie, all I can tell you is what you were telling me.Conquering this mountain is the first step in getting everything else you want.
麦琪:杰森,这能帮我赢得普利策奖吗?
Maggie: Jason, how does that help me win a Pulitzer?
杰森:问的好.你想放弃吗?
Jason: Good point.You want to leave?
麦琪:杰森,你不能让我当逃兵!
Maggie: Jason, you can't let me quit!
杰森:我还以为你想放弃呢.
Jason: I thought you wanted to quit.
麦琪:哦,我当然不会.我绝不能那么做.
Maggie: Well, of course I do!Which is exactly why I can't.
肯特:好样的.
Kent: That a-girl.
麦琪:谁也别来碰我.
Maggie: Touch me and you die!
肯特:好的,这就像我们练习的那样.
Kent: Okay, this'll be just like we practiced.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: Okay.
肯特:你要保持膝盖弯曲,你要注意力集中.
Kent: You want to keep your knees bent.You want to stay focused.Okay?
麦琪: 哦-哦.
Maggie: Uh-huh.
肯特:最重要的是放松.
Kent: And most of all, relax.
杰森:就像生孩子一样.
Jason: Just like having a baby.
麦琪:我会得脑震荡吗?
Maggie: Can I have an epidural?
肯特:准备好了?
Kent: Ready?
麦琪:一切准备好了.
Maggie: As ready as I'll ever be.
肯特:好的.我会把你慢慢地从山上放下去.放松点.
Ken: Okay.I'm gonna lower you down the mountain slowly.Nice &amp; easy.
麦琪:好的,亲爱的,我爱你.
Maggie: Okay.Honey, I love you.
杰森:我也爱你.
Jason: I love you, too.
麦琪:好了.
Maggie: Okay.
杰森:你会没事的.
Jason: You're gonna be fine.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: All right.
杰森:你做的很好.
Jason: You're fine.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: All right
杰森:杰森和麦琪:你练过的哦,是的……很好……下去了……就这样……很好……是的.
Jason and Maggie: You practiced...oh, yeah...looking good...it's working...that's it...it's working....yes...
麦琪:(笑)……我不会死了!
Maggie: (laughing)...I'm not gonna die!
杰森:对!
Jason: No!
麦琪:(笑)……这真的是很有意思!
Maggie: (laughing)...This could actually be fun!
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
肯特:好了.现在你准备好来个惊险的吗?
Ken: Okay.Now, you ready to try a push off?
麦琪:是的!
Maggie: Sure!
肯特:好的.1……2……3!
Ken: Okay.One...two...three!
杰森:哇!
Jason: Whoa!
麦琪:(笑)
Maggie: (laughing)
杰森:哇,好像撞到石头上了?
Jason: Whoa.Supposed to smack into the rock like that?
杰森:亲爱的,你还好吗?
Jason: Honey, are you all right?
麦琪:我很好.你呢?不,我,我,我觉得被卡住了.
Maggie: I'm fine.How are you?No.I, I, I think I'm stuck.
杰森:她被卡住了.她被卡住了.你必须帮帮她.
Jason: She's stuck.She's stuck.You gotta do something.
肯特:哦,一定是她的安全绳缠到下面的石头上了.
Ken: Well, her guideline's just tangled in that rock down there.
我们得下去把绳子解开.
One of us is gonna have to go down there and free it up.
杰森:好主意.
Jason: Good plan.
肯特:那个更有经验的人必须待在这里掌握绳子.
Ken: And the more experienced one is gonna have to stay here and anchor
the rope.
卢克:他们真的攀岩去了?
Luke: They're jumping off a mountain?
迈克:他们中年探险活动为我打开了机遇的窗户.今天我把咱家租给一个摄制组了,
Mike: Their midlife crisis is my window of opportunity.
500块钱啊.
You see, I rented the house to a film crew today.For five hundred bucks.
我唯一要做的就是给他看看我们有火灾保险.
And all I had to do was show 'em we had fire insurance.
卢克:真聪明.
Luke: Pretty smooth.
卢克:是的.呃,
Luke: Yeah, um, uh, I'm calling from our state-of-the-art kitchen.
我现在就是在我们现代化的厨房里打电话呢.他们这样有移动电话什么的,应有尽有.
They got, uh, mobile phones and everything.
迈克:是吗?哦,你爸爸怎么样?
Mike: Yeah?Well, how's your dad?
卢克:哦,他很好.
Luke: Oh, he's fine.
他刚才租了一个起重机把世界上最大的咖啡壶放到屋顶上了.
He just rented a crane to put the world's biggest coffee pot on the roof.
迈克:哦,这会吸引很多旅游者的.
Mike: Well, then that should pull in the tourists.
迈克:好的.我们想你,再见.
Mike: Okay.We miss ya.Bye.
本:嘿!
Ben: Hey!
迈克:嘿!对不起,舞会狂.你在这里没戏.
Mike: Hey!Sorry, party dog, but you've been fixed.
本:不行.肯尼带来一个放音师和一帮浓妆艳抹的姑娘.
Ben: No way!Kenny's bringing a DJ and a bunch of party girls wearing too
这个地方是我的.
much make-up.So this place is mine.
迈克:好的,好的.
Mike: All right, all right.I'll level with you, Ben.Now listen.
我把它留给你,本.现在听着,
Now, I don't need this place for me.
我不是自己需要这个地方,是一些城市里的贫苦孩子来参观.
I need it for a group of underprivileged inner-city kids.
本:真的?干什么?
Ben: Really?What for?
迈克:哦,这就像是郊区一日游什么的.本,
Mike: Well, it's kind of like a suburbia day-trip for 'em, Ben.
这些孩子有的从没见过草坪洒水车和其他一些城里没有的东西.
I mean, some of these kids have never even seen a lawn sprinkler,
or so much as a refrigerator magnet.
本:等等.你什么时候关心起贫苦儿童来了.
Ben: Wait.You don't care a rat's hat about underprivileged kids.
迈克:哦,是吗?
Mike: Oh, yeah?Well, here!
我说,你为什么不把这话说给小阿方索,曼纽尔和哈维听呢?
Why don't you tell that to little Alfonso, Manuel and Harvey.
本:你应该上周就通知我,我已经邀请整个学校的同学来了.
Ben: I wish you'd have told me this last week,
嘿!你在骗我!
before I invited the whole school.Hey!That's Menudo!
你买那个钱夹就是我陪你去的.
I was with you when you bought that wallet.
是不是准备和描着黑眼线的姑娘玩啊.
Get ready for some babes in heavy eyeliner.
麦琪:(喊叫,尖叫)
Maggie: (yelling, screaming)
杰森:我们给你解开了,你可以下去了.
Jason: We've got you untangled.You can go down now.
麦琪:你确认!
Maggie: Wanna bet!
麦琪和杰森:(喊叫)
Maggie and Jason: (yelling)
麦琪,这可以补偿许多没过的纪念日了.
Jason: Maggie, this ought to make up for a lot of anniversaries.
麦琪:亲爱的,我一直想着呢.
Maggie: Honey, I've been thinking.
杰森:哦,是不是因为这,我们才陷到这么危险的境地呢?那些石头上为什么会有红红的东西呢?
Jason: Well, isn't that what got us into this predicament in the first place?Why are there red stains all over those rocks?
麦琪:哦,杰森!别说了!我还指望你是个理性的人呢.
Maggie: Oh, Jason!Stop that!I'm counting on you to be the rational one.
杰森:哦-哦.你像风铃一样的摇摆,我很难保持理性,麦琪.
Jason: Uh-huh.Hard to be rational when you're dangling like a wind chime, Maggie.
麦琪:(叫喊)杰森,检查一下我的想法.
Maggie: (yelling) Jason, check my thinking here.
杰森:哦-哦.
Jason: Uh-huh.
麦琪:攀岩只是个象征.实际上,这并不能让我更优秀.
Maggie: Rappelling is just symbolic.It doesn't make me a better person in and of itself.
杰森:对.
Jason: True.
麦琪:所以,也许是因为工作紧张和到了更年期,
Maggie: So.Considering my career anxiety and mid-life panic,
我才想做点疯狂的事.
I might just be doing something crazy.
杰森:完全赞同.
Jason: No argument here.
麦琪:所以,亲爱的,请告诉我忘记这一切,我们回家吧.
Maggie: So, honey, please tell me it's okay to forget this and go home.
杰森:这就是你想让我说的吗,麦琪?
Jason: Is that what you want me to say, Maggie?
麦琪:帮帮我,杰森.
Maggie: Work with me here, Jason.
杰森:好吧,放弃,回家.
Jason: It's okay to quit and go home!
麦琪:你必须要说放弃吗?
Maggie: Did you have to say quit?
你不能说"坚持下去"或"清醒一下"吗?
Couldn't you say "hang in there" or "come to your senses?"
杰森:好吧,麦琪.这种情况下有两种选择:上去或下去.
Jason: All right, Maggie.There are two ways out of this situation.Up or down.
麦琪:就两种吗?
Maggie: That's it?
杰森:哦,我很想和你在这里共度余生,
Jason: Well, we could spend our golden years here,
但我怕孩子们不来看我们.
but I doubt the kids would visit.
麦琪:哦,杰森.我觉得这一点都不好笑.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, I don't think that's very funny.
杰森:麦琪,想让我直说吗?好吧,那我就直说.
Jason: Maggie, want straight talk, sweetheart?Well, here it is.Okay.
要么你现在就让肯特把你拉回到安全地带,还像以前那样的生活.
You can either have Kent pull you back up into that comfort zone and be
这很好.要么你就坚强起来,麦琪.
the person you've always been, which is fine.Or you can be tough, Maggie.
面对大山显示你才是征服者.这种冒险你到死也不会忘记……我们的年龄也不小了.
You can show this mountain who's boss.
You can have an adventure you'll remember 'til your dying day...
which isn't for many years.
麦琪:好的.好的,肯特.好的,准备好了吗?
Maggie: Okay.Okay, Kent.All right.Are you ready?
肯特:(喊叫)来吧!
Kent: (yelling) Go for it!
麦琪:1…2…3!(喊叫)黛比·迪哈特,这才是普利策奖!
Maggie: One...two....three!(yelling) Pulitzer this, Debbie Teighart!
迈克:放弃吧,本.我比你大,比你有经验.
Mike: Give it up, Ben.I'm older, more experienced than you are.
本:你都生锈了,过时了.
Ben: You're rusty and out of practice.
迈克:哦,也许你应该问问自己:你的晚会呢?
Mike: Well, maybe you should ask yourself this: where's your party?
本:那你的摄制组呢?
Ben: Where's your film crew?
迈克:他们快来了.但你的晚会泡汤了.
Mike: They'll be here.But your party is history.
我放出话去了,你有舞伴了.
I spread the word that you were having chaperones.
本:你太幼稚了.我早知道这样,
Ben: You're so simple.
就告诉每个人本的舞伴就是你们.
I knew that, and told everybody the chaperones were 19-year-old au-pairs.
而你不知道的是,我给你的摄制组打了电话,
What you don't know is that I called your film crew and rescheduled for
把日期推迟到了复活节.
Easter.
迈克:你这个该死的骗子.
Mike: Poor, deceived wretch.
可他们知道只有密码指令才算数.
They know only to take instructions with a codeword.
本:三角洲黎明?
Ben: Delta Dawn?
迈克:你知道?
Mike: You knew?
本:我知道的密码指令多着呢.再见了,摄制组.
Ben: There are other extensions in this house.Hasta la vista, film crew.
迈克:别高兴的太早.也许你应该去大门看看吧.我觉得那里应该有什么东西.
Mike: Well, before you gloat, maybe you should check out the front door.I think there's something out there.
本:哦,当然有什么东西了.现场舞会,本主办.
Ben: Oh, there's something out there all right.Instant party.Just add Ben.
本:警戒线?不得越过?
Ben: Police lines?Do not cross?
迈克:念念通知.
Mike: Read the sign.
本:因患淋巴腺鼠疫,舞会取消!
Ben: Party is cancelled due to the bubonic plague!
迈克:再见了,舞会.
Mike: Hasta la vista, party.
本:你这么做到底想干什么?你在这屋子里猖狂好多年了!什么时候才轮到我.
Ben: What'd you go and do that for?C'mon, you've been scamming freely in this house for years!When's it gonna be my turn?
迈克:嘿,嘿.你轮到过.我得扁桃体炎的时候.
Mike: Hey, you had your turn!When I had my tonsils out.
本:我才3岁.
Ben: I was three!
迈克:你知道,本,我一直在想,昨晚你也没睡好吧?
Mike: You know, Ben, I've been thinking.Was your night as miserable as mine?
本:谁说的?我睡得好极了.
Ben: Are you kidding?I watched "Star Search."
迈克:噢.我们现实点吧.我500块钱没有弄到手.你的舞会也没开成.
Mike: Well, let's face it.I mean, I didn't get my five hundred dollars.You didn't get to have your party.
本:你在说什么呢?
Ben: So what are you saying?
迈克:哦,我是说,
Mike: Well, I'm saying that if I haven't used a scam for one calendar year,
如果我一年不耍心眼,这里就是你说了算.
it's all yours.
本:也包括开爸爸的车去机场,
Ben: Does that include taking dad's car to the airport,
并用作出租车吗?
and using it as a gypsy cab?
克莉丝:看谁来了!
Chrissy: Look who's here!
迈克:嘿,回来了!
Ben: Mom, dad, you're alive!
本:妈妈,爸爸,你们还活着!
Mike: Hey, guys!
麦琪:是的!猜猜看.我做到了!
Maggie: Yep!And guess what?I did it!
迈克:太好了!祝贺你!真不敢相信!我的父母去攀岩了.
Mike: All right!Congratulations!I can't believe it!My parents; rappelling.
麦琪:(笑)实际上,一架直升机救了你爸爸.
Maggie: (laughing) Actually, a helicopter came for your father.
麦琪:嘿,攀岩可不是我的目标.
Jason: Hey, rapelling wasn't on my list.
麦琪:好了.我感觉自己完全变了样.没有什么我做不到的了.
Maggie: Well, I feel like a whole new Maggie.There's nothing I can do now.
杰森:幸亏定目标之前蹦极还没出现呢.
Jason: Just like you Maggie before they invented bungee jumping.
麦琪:噢,亲爱的.蹦极!多好的主意啊!我去打电话为我们这一周安排一次.
Maggie: Oh, honey, bungee jumping!What a great idea!I'm gonna go make an appointment for us this week.
杰森:别!别!别!Maggie,不要.
Jason: No!No!No!Mag, no.
麦琪:还记得我昨晚在宾馆给你说的话了?
Maggie: Do you remember last night at the lodge?
杰森:是的,我记得.我和你妈要去……蹦极.
Jason: Yes, I do.Your mother and I are going....bungee jumping.
杰森:你们能不能帮我把行李下卸下来?
Jason: You guys wanna help me unpack the car?
克莉丝:爸爸,我能不能也去蹦极啊?
Chrissy: Daddy, can I jump over Benji, too?
麦琪:(叹气)(写)绳索有半英寸粗,重量很轻,我很轻易就绑在安全带上.
Maggie: (sighing) (writing) The rope was half an inch in diameter, light enough for me to carry on my belt without noticing.
但我悬挂在那里.我和死亡之间只有这根绳子.我想到了丈夫,家庭和工作.
我终于认识到我是一个幸运的女人,能够拥有这一切..
00:22:41,300
But there I hung; with only that rope between me and death.I saw my husband, my family, my career. And I realized that I'm one of those lucky women who really does have it all.